Guide to the Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records, 1934-2005 and undated RL.00090
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Creative Department Series, 1980s-2003 and undated, bulk 1997-2002; 62 boxes
  - Print Advertisements Subseries, 1997-2002 and undated
    - Alphabetical List
      - Loto/Moët
        - Undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - MacQuarie University, 2001, boxes CR35, CR36 (Box CR51A)
      - McIllhenny-Tabasco, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Mercedes Benz
        - 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
        - 2000, boxes CR21, CR24 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, box CR31 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, box CR42 (Box CR51A)
        - Undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - MG, 2002, box CR42 (Box CR51A)
      - Millennium Foundation
        - 1999, box CR16 (Box CR51A)
        - 2000, box CR28 (Box CR51A)
      - Mini Cooper, 2002, box CR45 (Box CR51A)
      - Mova Regional, 2000, box CR28 (Box CR51A)
      - Murata, 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - National Geographic, 2002, box CR50 (Box CR51A)
      - New Moment Design, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - New World Mobility
        - 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, box CR49 (Box CR51A)
      - No Regrets, 2001, box CR36 (Box CR51A)
      - Nokia
        - 1999, boxes CR11, CR18 (Box CR51A)
        - 2000, boxes CR23, CR24 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, boxes CR32, CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, boxes CR49, CR50 (Box CR51A)
        - Undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - NZ Cheese, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Odol mouthwash, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - Once, 2001, boxes CR33, CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Onida, 2002, box CR46 (Box CR51A)
      - Organ Donation Center of Thailand, 1999, box CR16 (Box CR51A)
      - PacSun, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Pearl & Dean, 1999, box CR13 (Box CR51A)
      - Peugeot, 1999, box CR13 (Box CR51A)
      - Pfizer, 1999, box CR13 (Box CR51A)
      - Pharmacia Upjohn, 2002, box CR42 (Box CR51A)
      - Photonica, 1999, box CR13 (Box CR51A)
      - Polenguinho Cheese, 2002, box CR43 (Box CR51A)
      - Pripp's Breweries
        - 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
        - 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Project Hope China, 1999, box CR16 (Box CR51A)
      - Pro-Plus, 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Prostate Cancer Research Foundation, 2002, box CR47 (Box CR51A)
      - Provident Financial Services
        - 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
        - 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Raw Bar, 2001, box CR36 (Box CR51A)
      - RCI, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Revista Negocios, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Roche-Rennie, 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Rover
        - 2000, boxes CR21, CR24, CR26 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, boxes CR33, CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, box CR42 (Box CR51A)
      - Royal Flying Doctor Service, 2002, box CR47 (Box CR51A)
      - Royal Mail
        - 2000, boxes CR23, CR24, CR28 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, boxes CR33, CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - Undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - Rumsmiddeldirektoratet, 1999, box CR16 (Box CR51A)
      - Saab, 2002, box CR43 (Box CR51A)
      - Safeway, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - SAP.com, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Save Our Kids, 2002, box CR47 (Box CR51A)
      - Schwarzkopf, 2000, box CR26 (Box CR51A)
      - Seat
        - 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, boxes CR34, CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, boxes CR43, CR46, CR49 (Box CR51A)
      - Sky Television, 2002, boxes CR43, CR46, CR49 (Box CR51A)
      - Smithkline Beecham, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Solar Inc.
        - 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - Undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - Sonae.com, 2002, box CR43 (Box CR51A)
      - Sony, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Spectranet, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Spectrum United, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Stavanger Museum, 2002, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - Stora, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Suntours, 1999, boxes CR11, CR13 (Box CR51A)
      - Superdrug, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Sydney 2000 Apparel, 2001, boxes CR33, CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Taco Bell, 2002, box CR44 (Box CR51A)
      - Taj Bengal, 2002, box CR44 (Box CR51A)
      - TDC Mobil, 2002, box CR44 (Box CR51A)
      - Tennis Canada, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Thames water
        - 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, boxes CR44, CR50 (Box CR51A)
      - Thredbo, undated, box CR51A (Box CR51A)
      - Time, 2002, boxes CR44, CR46 (Box CR51A)
      - Toyota
        - 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Trojan, 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Unicef, 1999, box CR16 (Box CR51A)
      - USM Modular Furniture, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - UUNet, 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
      - Vala Shopping Mall, 1999, box CR11 (Box CR51A)
      - Varma, 2000, box CR28 (Box CR51A)
      - Verizon
        - 2001, box CR35 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, box CR46 (Box CR51A)
      - Villacher, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Volkswagen
        - 2000, box CR22 (Box CR51A)
        - 2001, boxes CR35, CR36 (Box CR51A)
        - 2002, boxes CR44, CR46, CR50 (Box CR51A)
      - Wahindia.com, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Warner Lambert, 2002, box CR45 (Box CR51A)
      - Warner Lambert India, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Wella, 2002, box CR45 (Box CR51A)
      - Wendy's ice cream, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Westfall Shopping Centre, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Whitehall/Chapstick, undated, box CR51 (Box CR51A)
      - Whitney Museum, 2000, box CR22 (Box CR51A)
      - Woolworth's, 2001, box CR36 (Box CR51A)
      - Yahoo.com, 2002, box CR45 (Box CR51A)
      - Yellow Pages, 2002, box CR46 (Box CR51A)
      - Zanussi, 2000, box CR21 (Box CR51A)
      - Zappy Baby, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Zenith, 2001, box CR33 (Box CR51A)
      - Zoo Safari, 2002, box CR45 (Box CR51A)
  - Office Files Subseries, 1980s-2003 and undated
    Correspondence, clippings, listings and printed materials relating to creative competitions, creative standards, databases (such as Adbank) and information technology, as well as files relating to executives such as John Fawcett, supporting materials for annual reports and departmental events. The files include calls for submissions, informational brochures and awards booklets for many of the major advertising industry awards competitions, as well as correspondence and submission forms for Bates's own Best of Bates competitions. Some of the images in the awards booklets represent Bates award-winning entries, but there is little documentation about the actual entry submissions themselves, nor are the actual submission procedures for external awards competitions well-documented here. Included is a run of the Creative Department's newsletter Shout! Arranged alphabetically. Therein, printed materials are further arranged chronologically.
    - General office files (Box CR52)
      - Account management presentation, undated (Box CR52)
      - Adbank
        - Awards, 2001 (Box CR52)
        - Digitizing, 2001 (Box CR52)
        - Long Term, 2001 (Box CR52)
        - Print, 2001 (Box CR52)
        - Reference, 2001 (Box CR52)
      - Awards shows-contact information, 1999-2000 (Box CR52)
      - Bates UK international television productions, 2002 (Box CR52)
        from Barry Stephenson
      - Charitable works requests, 2002 (Box CR52)
        file of Denise Williams
      - Chelsea Piers (Creative expedition), 1998 (Box CR52)
      - Client seminars, 1998 (Box CR52)
      - Cordiant (CCG) Annual Report-creative visuals, 1999 (Box CR52)
      - Cordiant Confidential (video magazine), 2003 (Box CR52)
      - Creative Department events, 1998-1999 (Box CR52)
      - Creative Infobank classifications, 1998 (Box CR52)
      - Creative Standards Conference, 1995, 2 folders (Box CR52)
      - Creative Standards Council, 1995 (Box CR52)
      - Current award show list, 2000 (Box CR52)
      - Daily activities log, 2002 Aug. 9-2003 Feb. 24 (Box CR52)
      - Global Creative Center, 1998 (Box CR52)
      - Information technology-warranties, 1996 (Box CR52)
      - Internet, 1998 (Box CR52)
      - Marketing, brand identity information, undated (Box CR52)
      - Newsletter, Shout!, 1997-2000
        - History (Box CR52)
        - Issues
          - 1-3, 1997 Sept.-1998 Dec., 3 folders (Box CR52)
          - 4-8, 1999 Apr.-2000 Apr., 6 folders (Box CR53)
      - North American client list, 2002 (Box CR53)
      - Outdoor advertising examples (color laminates), undated (Box CR53)
      - People
        - Fawcett, John, 1998-2002 (Box CR53)
        - Kølle, Hans-Henrik, 2001 (Box CR53)
        - Theophilakis, Aris, 2000 (Box CR53)
        - Whitehead, Bill, 2000 (Box CR53)
      - Photographers
        - Brodey, Ivan, 1998-1999 (Box CR53)
        - Gehrke, Peter, 1998 (Box CR53)
      - Print library, 1998 (Box CR53)
      - Strategic planning presentation, undated (Box CR53)
      - TV Guide, Top 50 Television Commercials, 1999 (Box CR53)
      - Video library, 1998 (Box CR53)
      - World television standards (tape size and format), 1999 (Box CR53)
    - Award shows
      - 141 Worldwide submissions, 2001-2003 (Box CR53)
      - Advertising Age (Box CR54)
        - Best awards, 1998 (Box CR54)
        - Global Network, 1998 (Box CR54)
      - Advertising Hall of Fame luncheon, 1996 Mar. 26 (Box CR54)
        Induction of William Backer
      - Adweek best spots, 2002-2003 (Box CR54)
      - Agency of the Year submissions, 1999 (Box CR54)
      - AME awards, 1999 (Box CR54)
        Advertising Marketing Effectiveness
      - Cannes festival, 1988-2002, 8 folders (Box CR54)
      - Cannes festival, 1988-2002 (continued), 2 folders (Box CR55)
      - Clio Awards, 1997-2001, 6 folders (Box CR55)
      - Cresta Awards, 1998, 5 folders (Box CR55)
      - Effie Awards, 1997-2003 (Box CR55)
      - Globals festival, 1998 (Bates Sweden) (Box CR56)
      - Healthcom Gracie awards show list, 1998 (Box CR56)
      - International advertising shows-Ukraine, 1999 (Box CR56)
      - International automotive advertising awards, 1998 (Box CR56)
      - International Tourism, Travel and Leisure advertising festival, 1998, 2 folders (Box CR56)
      - Mobius awards, 1998 (Box CR56)
      - Worldwide creative awards
        - 1980s-1999, 5 folders (Box CR56)
        - 2000-2001, 5 folders (Box CR57)
        - 2002-2003, 6 folders (Box CR58)
    - Internal creative competition (Bates Best)
      - 1996, 1998-1999, 17 folders (Box CR58)
      - 2000-2001, 29 folders (Box CR59)
      - 2001, 32 folders (Box CR60)
      - 2001-2003, 18 folders (Box CR61)
    - Media coverage, 1998-2003 (Box CR62)
      Articles and clippings relating to creative awards
- Financial Records Series, 1941-1993, 11 boxes
  Statements of accounts, ledgers, computer-generated sales analyses, tax information and trial balances dating between 1941-1993. There is not a complete run of any one kind of report. Organized alphabetically by type of report and chronologically therein.
  - Financial statements and accounts audits, 1941-1971, 6 folders (Box FN1)
  - General ledgers, 1955-1984
    - 1955-1957, 2 folders (Box FN1)
    - 1959-1965, folders 1-8 of 12 (Box FN2)
    - 1959-1965 (continued), folders 9-12 of 12 (Box FN3)
    - 1969-1975 (Box FN4)
    - 1980-1984, folders 1-3 of 10 (Box FN3)
    - 1980-1984 (continued), folders 4-10 of 10 (Box FN5)
  - Sales analysis, 1986-1989, folders 1-4 of 14 (Box FN6)
  - Sales analysis, 1986-1989 (continued), folders 5-9 of 14 (Box FN7)
  - Sales analysis, 1986-1989 (continued), Folders 10-12 of 14 (Box FN8)
  - Sales analysis, 1986-1989 (continued), Folders 13-14 of 14 (Box FN9)
  - Taxes, 1991-1993, 4 folders (Box FN9A)
  - Trial balances, 1984 Nov.-1985 Jan., Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box FN10)
  - Trial balances, 1984 Nov.-1985 Jan. (continued), Folder 3 of 3 (Box FN11)
- Human Resources Department Series, 1941-2002 and undated, bulk 1970-1998, 49 boxes
  Memoranda, lists of executives, manuals on company policies and procedures, along with information on benefits, new employee orientation and training and other printed materials created or used by the Bates Human Resources department. The series is organized into eight subseries--Administrative Files, Clients, Employee Information, Media, Meetings, Memoranda, Personnel Files, and Printed Materials. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Administrative Files Subseries, 1955-2000
    Organizational charts, shareholder lists and files on mergers (eSpecialy Bates with Backer Spielvogel) and acquisition projects (including Kenyon & Eckhardt, Needham, Harper & Steers, and Tracy Locke agencies) and Bates' takeover by Saatchi & Saatchi. Included is information on Bates' original incorporation in 1955. Organized into two categories--General files and Mergers and acquisitions--and alphabetically therein.
    - General files (Box HR1)
      - 25th anniversary, 1965 (Box HR1)
      - AAF-Hall of Fame, Ted Bates, 1982 (Box HR1)
      - Benefits, 1994 (Box HR1)
      - Deficit termination of Prudential contract, 1987-1988 (Box HR1)
      - Financials, 1984-1987 (Box HR1)
      - Incorporation of Ted Bates Company, 1955 (Box HR1)
      - Index sheet, 1977-1984, 2 folders (Box HR1)
      - MBA brocure, 1970-1971 (Box HR1)
      - Option agreements, 1982 (Box HR1)
      - Organizational charts, 1987-2000, folders 1-7 of 12 (Box HR1)
      - Organizational charts, 1987-2000, folders 8-12 of 12 (Box HR2)
      - Plans and goals, 1983-1991 (Box HR2)
      - Profit-sharing, 1975 (Box HR2)
      - Public relations, 1987-1988 (Box HR2)
      - Shareholders
        - Class A shareholder listing by company, 1985, 2 folders (Box HR2)
        - Shareholders lists, 1986 (Box HR2)
        - Stockholder's agreement, 1969 (Box HR2)
      - Tax case, 1964 (Box HR2)
    - Mergers and acquisitions
      - Co-acquisitions and mergers, 1970-1987
        - American affiliates, 1974-1985 (Box HR2)
        - Australia, 1964-1988 (Box HR2)
        - Europe, 1959-1984 (Box HR2)
      - Companies
        - AC&R Advertising, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box HR2)
        - Campbell Mithun, 1976-1979 (Box HR2)
        - Caribiner, 1976-1977 (Box HR3)
        - Chiat Day, 1979-1982 (Box HR3)
        - Kenyon & Eckhardt, 1978-1979 (Box HR3)
        - Needham Harper & Steers, 1976-1977 (Box HR3)
        - Tracy-Locke Advertising, 1980-1981 (Box HR3)
        - Y & R International, 1974-1979 (Box HR3)
      - Saatchi & Saatchi takeover
        - Bates and Backer Spielvogel merger, 1986-1988, 3 folders (Box HR3)
        - Bates financials, transferred to Saatchi, 1989 (Box HR3)
        - Bates/Saatchi post-merger, 1987 (Box HR3)
        - Saatchi mergers, 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box HR3)
        - Shareholders termination guarantee, 1986 (Box HR3)
  - Clients Subseries, 1955-1993 and undated
    Primarily lists of clients and account information. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Client lists, 1962-1985, 1992-1993 (Box HR4)
    - Clients--Accounts, 1955-1987, 2 folders (Box HR5)
    - Clients--New products introduced, undated (Box HR5)
    - Domestic client brand report, 1978-1985, 3 folders (Box HR5)
  - Employee Benefits Subseries, 1962-2002 and undated
    Orientation materials for new employees, benefits packages (insurance, profit sharing, retirement), job descriptions, manuals for supervisors, performance evaluation guidelines and training materials. Included is information on the Unique Selling Proposition (USP) as Bates' guiding philosophy, employee training in USP, and case studies of significant USP campaigns, such as Certs and Nicorette. USP was the constant corporate principle that survived Bates' long history of name changes and mergers. The first part of the series is arranged alphabetically by company or subsidiary name, followed by files relating to USP that are arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - AC&R Advertising, Inc. (Box HR6)
      - Benefits, undated (Box HR6)
      - Policy manuals, 1988-1991, 2 folders (Box HR6)
    - Backer Spielvogel Bates
      - Benefits, 1992 (Box HR6)
      - Chrysler Building handbook, undated (Box HR6)
      - Creative Choices benefits plans, 1991-1992 (Box HR6)
      - Employee handbooks
        - Backer Spielvogel Bates (BSB) Canada, 1989 (Box HR6)
        - Other offices, 1987 (Box HR6)
      - Employee presentation, undated (Box HR6)
      - Insurance, 1991 (Box HR6)
      - Life insurance-Grandfathered, 1987 (Box HR6)
      - Training programs
        - AMP (Advanced Management Program), 1994 (Box HR6)
        - International training program, undated (Box HR6)
    - Bates
      - Benefits plans, 1965-1988 and undated, Folder 1 of 2 (Box HR6)
      - Benefits plans, 1965-1988 and undated (continued), Folder 2 of 2 (Box HR7)
      - Benefits-Miscellaneous brochures, 1963-1994 and undated (Box HR7)
      - Employee communications, 1988 and undated (Box HR7)
      - Employee handbooks and pamphlets, 1958-1968 and undated
        - The Bates Book, 1972-1982 (Box HR7)
      - Employee presentation, Bates 141 Worldwide, undated (Box HR7)
      - Global services presentation, 2000, 2 folders (Box HR7)
      - Introduction to Bates, undated (Box HR7)
      - Job descriptions, 1985, 3 folders (Box HR8)
      - Performance appraisal manuals, undated (Box HR8)
      - Policy manuals, 1969-1972 (Box HR8)
      - Profit sharing and retirement, 1962-1987 (Box HR8)
      - Retiree medical coverage grandfathered, 1990 (Box HR8)
      - Retirement plan, unclaimed benefit payments, 1989 (Box HR8)
      - Training (Box HR9)
        - General, 1988-1991 (Box HR9)
        - Account Management development program, 1988-1989 (Box HR9)
        - AMP (Advanced Management Program), 1989-1996
          - AMP handbook, 1989, 4 folders (Box HR9)
          - Correspondence, 1996 (Box HR9)
          - Pre-work, undated, folders 1-2 of 4 (Box HR9)
          - Pre-work, undated, folders 3-4 of 4 (Box HR10)
          - Simulation scenarios, undated, 3 folders (Box HR10)
        - Bates Basics, 2000 Nov 10 (Box HR10)
        - Creating Client Commitment, undated (Box HR11)
        - Media glossary, undated (Box HR11)
        - Professional development programs, 2001 (Box HR11)
        - USA managers program, 1999, 2 folders (Box HR11)
    - Cordiant
      - Group money purchase plan, undated (Box HR11)
      - Performance appraisal manual, 2002, 2 folders (Box HR11)
    - Saatchi & Saatchi
      - Training study, 1991, Jan. (Box HR11)
    - Unique Selling Proposition (USP) (Box HR12)
      - Advertising
        - Asia, 1997 (Box HR12)
        - Europe, 1997, 2 folders (Box HR12)
        - Latin America, 1998 (Box HR12)
        - USA, 1996 (Box HR12)
      - American Academy of Advertising, 1997 (Box HR12)
      - Bates heritage - USP, 1997 (Box HR12)
      - Branding
        - Brand equity research, undated (Box HR12)
        - Brand essence, undated (Box HR12)
        - Brand interrogation, 1997 (Box HR12)
      - Client advertisements, undated (Box HR12)
      - Clippings, 1984-1997 (Box HR12)
      - Creative brief, 1996 (Box HR12)
      - Econometric modeling, 1997-1998 (Box HR12)
      - Essay on advertising strategy, undated (Box HR12)
      - Handbooks, 1988-1997, 2 folders (Box HR12)
      - Improving the process, 1996 (Box HR12)
      - Planner, undated (Box HR12)
      - Presentation, 1998 (Box HR12)
      - Promotional material, undated (Box HR12)
      - Reality in Advertising, 1996, 2 folders (Box HR12)
      - Research tools, undated (Box HR12)
      - Training (Box HR13)
        - General, 1997 (Box HR13)
        - Correspondence, 1997, 2 folders (Box HR13)
        - Television commercials, 1997 (Box HR13)
        - Training--International, 1997 (Box HR13)
        - Training--U.S.A., 1997 (Box HR13)
      - USP case studies
        - Certs
          - Information on competitors, 1982-1997 (Box HR13)
          - Ingredients and marketing information, 1997 (Box HR13)
          - Meeting, 1997, Apr. 18 (Box HR13)
          - Prework
            - Background, 1995-1996 (Box HR13)
            - Brand interrogation, undated (Box HR13)
            - Brand marketing agenda, 1993-1997 (Box HR13)
            - Brand wheel, 1995 (Box HR13)
            - Understanding consumers, 1992-1995 (Box HR13)
            - Understanding the brand, 1991-1995 (Box HR13)
          - Product information, 1997 (Box HR13)
          - Report on Safari consumer groups, 1996 (Box HR13)
          - Role-playing competitive analysis, undated (Box HR13)
        - Nabisco, 1995-1996 (Box HR14)
        - Nicorette, 1997 (Box HR14)
        - Safeway, 1997 (Box HR14)
        - Warner Lambert/American Chicle Group, situation assessment, 1996, 2 books (Box HR14)
      - Traveling road show speeches, undated (Box HR14)
      - Miscellaneous, 1996-1997 (Box HR14)
  - Media Subseries, 1950-1999
    Clippings and articles about Bates, Bates executives (including Ted Bates and Rosser Reeves), clients and competitors, media department publications and press releases. Organized into four categories--Articles and clippings, Media Department files, Press releases, and Scrapbooks. Files are arranged alphabetically, except for the press releases, which are arranged chronologically.
    - Articles and clippings (Box HR15)
      - Advertising campaigns, 1968-1985 (Box HR15)
      - Articles about Rosser Reeves, 1955-1987 (Box HR15)
      - Articles about Ted Bates, 1950-1982 (Box HR15)
      - Backer & Spielvogel clippings file, 1979-1987 (Box HR15)
      - Bates corporate history clippings file, 1955-1968, 2 folders (Box HR15)
      - Billings, 1958-1975 (Box HR15)
      - Cybics Computer Company, 1969-1971 (Box HR15)
      - Data Processing Department, 1967 (Box HR15)
      - FTC investigations, 1957-1972 (Box HR15)
      - In the News clipping collections, 1987
        - Bates/Saatchi (Box HR15)
        - Executive Profiles (Box HR15)
      - International operations articles, 1965-1986 (Box HR15)
      - Medical group, 1967-1972 (Box HR15)
      - Moving plans, 1968-1969 (Box HR15)
      - New York division, 1969-1983 (Box HR15)
      - New York Times articles, 1976-1979, folders 1-6 of 12 (Box HR15)
      - New York Times articles, 1976-1979 continued), folders 6-12 of 12 (Box HR16)
      - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1974-1992, folders 1-5 of 11 (Box HR16)
      - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1974-1992, folders 6-11 of 11 (Box HR17)
    - Media Department
      - AAAA file, 1987 (Box HR17)
      - Clippings, 1960-1986 (Box HR17)
      - Miscellaneous publications, undated, 2 folders (Box HR17)
    - Press releases (Box HR18)
      - 1996 June 6, Bates Worldwide chairman and CEO defines new paradigm unifying interactive and conventional media, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 June 11, Bates USA study pinpoints potential of virtual reality for travel sales and marketing, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 June 12, Bates Southwest picks up Barry's Jewelers assignments, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 July 7, Bates USA launches its internet website, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 July 17, Bates promotion group named agency of record for two Jose Cuervo brands, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Aug. 7, BLGK, South Africa's largest independent advertising agency, joins Bates Worldwide Network, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Sept. 19, American Wrestling Federation/ BKS/ Bates Entertainment, 3 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Oct. 1, Bates USA wins Department of Defense JRAP contract, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Oct. 1, Bates Worldwide and Scholz & Friends form new relationship, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Oct. 11, CPC Baking Business consolidates its brands at Bates USA, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Oct. 24, Bates USA awarded U.S. Dept. of Defense DRMS account, 4 folders (Box HR18)
      - 1996 Oct. 29, Silverman, Marylin, guest speaker at Columbia, 4 folders (Box HR18)